The Highline
الهايلاين
is an old, elevated rail line
هو خط سكك حديد قديم مرتفع
that runs for a mile and a half right through Manhattan.
يمتد على طول ميل ونصف عبر مانهاتن.
And it was originally a freight line
وقد كان أصلا خط شحن
that ran down 10th Ave.
يمتد على طول الجادة العاشرة.
And it became known as "Death Avenue"
وقد صار معروفا ب: "جادة الموت"
because so many people were run over by the trains
لأن الكثير من الناس دهستهم القطارات
that the railroad hired a guy on horseback to run in front,
إلى درجة أن خط السكة الحديدة وظف شخصا يمتطي جوادا ليجري أمامه،
and he became known as the "West Side Cowboy."
وقد صار يعرف ب "راعي بقر الجهة الغربية."
But even with a cowboy,
ولكن حتى بوجود راعي بقر،
about one person a month
حوالي شخص واحد كل شهر
was killed and run over.
ماتوا دهسا.
So they elevated it.
وبالتالي رفعوا مستواها.
They built it 30 ft. in the air, right through the middle of the city.
بنوها على ارتفاع 30 قدما، مرورا بوسط المدينة.
But with the rise of interstate trucking,
لكن مع ظهور حركة الشاحنات بين الولايات،
it was used less and less.
لم يعد يستخدم بكثرة.
And by 1980, the last train rode.
وبحلول 1980، مر فيه آخر قطار.
It was a train loaded with frozen turkeys -- they say, at Thanksgiving --
كان قطارا مشحونا بديوك رومية مجمدة -- يقولون أثناء عيد الشكر --
from the meatpacking district.
من منطقة تعليب اللحوم.
And then it was abandoned.
ومن ثم تم التخلي عنها.
And I live in the neighborhood,
وأنا أعيش في المنطقة،
and I first read about it in the New York Times,
وقد قرأت عن الأمر أولا في النيويورك تايمز،
in an article that said it was going to be demolished.
في مقال يقول أنه سيتم هدمه.
And I assumed someone was working
وقد افترضت أن أحدهم يعمل
to preserve it or save it
على حمايته والمحافظة عليه
and I could volunteer,
وأستطيع التطوع،
but I realized no one was doing anything.
لكنني أدركت أنه لا أحد كان يفعل شيئا.
I went to my first community board meeting --
ذهبت أول مرة إلى اجتماع مجلس محلي --
which I'd never been to one before --
وأنا لم أحضر اجتماعا من نوعه من قبل --
and sat next to another guy named Joshua David,
وجلست بجانب شخص آخر يدعى جوشوا ديفيد،
who's a travel writer.
والذي هو كاتب أسفار.
And at the end of the meeting, we realized
وفي نهاية الإجتماع، أدركنا
we were the only two people that were sort of interested in the project;
أننا الشخصان الوحيدان الذي كانا نوعا ما مهتمين بالمشروع؛
most people wanted to tear it down.
معظم الناس يريدون تحطيمه.
So we exchanged business cards,
وهكذا تبادلنا بطاقات الأعمال،
and we kept calling each other
وواصلنا الإتصال ببعضنا البعض
and decided to start this organization,
وقررنا أن نبدأ منظمة،
Friends of the High Line.
أصدقاء الهايلاين.
And the goal at first
والهدف كان في البدء
was just saving it from demolition,
حمايته من التدمير فقط ،
but then we also wanted to figure out what we could do with it.
لكننا كذلك أردنا معرفة ما الذي يمكننا أن نفعل له.
And what first attracted me, or interested me,
وما اجتذبني أولا، أو أثار اهتمامي
was this view from the street --
هو هذا المنظر من الشارع --
which is this steel structure,
والذي هو هذه البنية الفولاذية،
sort of rusty,
صدئ نوعا ما،
this industrial relic.
هذه البقايا الصناعية.
But when I went up on top,
لكن حين صعدت الى الأعلى،
it was a mile and a half of wildflowers
كان امتداد ميل ونصف من الأزهار البرية
running right through the middle of Manhattan
يمتد وسط منهاتن
with views of the Empire State Building
بمناظر لمبنى إمباير ستيت
and the Statue of Liberty and the Hudson River.
وتمثال الحرية ونهر هدسون.
And that's really where we started,
وهذا فعلا حيث بدأنا،
the idea coalesced around, let's make this a park,
تكونت الفكرة، لنجعله متنزها،
and let's have it be sort of inspired
ولنجعلها نوعا ما ملهمة
by this wildscape.
من طرف هذه البرية.
At the time, there was a lot of opposition.
آنذاك، كان هناك الكثير من المعارضة.
Mayor Giuliani wanted to tear it down.
العمدة جولياني أراد تحطيمه.
I'm going to fast-forward through a lot of lawsuits
سأتقدم سريعا نحو الأمام وأتجاوز الكثير من الدعاوى القضائية
and a lot of community engagement.
والكثير من المشاركات في المجتمع المحلي.
Mayor Bloomberg came in office, he was very supportive,
تولى العمدة بلومبرغ الولاية، وكان في غاية الدعم،
but we still had to make the economic case.
لكن لا زال علينا أن نهيئ قضيتنا اقتصاديا.
This was after 9/11;
كان هذا بعد الحادي عشر من سبتمبر؛
the city was in tough times.
كانت المدينة تمر بظروف عصيبة.
So we commissioned an economic feasibility study
وهكذا فوضنا مهمة إجراء دراسة جدوى اقتصادية
to try to make the case.
لمحاولة بناء قضية.
And it turns out, we got those numbers wrong.
والحاصل أن الأرقام كانت خاطئة.
We thought it would cost 100 million dollars to build.
كنا نظن أنه سيكلف 100 مليون دولار لبنائه.
So far it's cost about 150 million.
لكن لحد الآن كلف 150 مليون دولار.
And the main case was,
والقضية الرئيسية كانت،
this is going to make good economic sense for the city.
أن هذا كان سيكون ذا قيمة إقتصادية للمدينة.
So we said over a 20-year time period,
لذا قلنا بأنه في غضون فترة 20 سنة،
the value to the city in increased property values
القيمة التي سيضيفها للمدينة في قيم زيادة العقارات
and increased taxes
وزيادة الضرائب
would be about 250 million.
ستكون حوالي 250 مليون.
That was enough. It really got the city behind it.
هذا كان كافيا. جعلت المدينة تدعمنا.
It turns out we were wrong on that.
واتضح أننا كنا مخطئين في ذلك.
Now people estimate it's created about a half a billion dollars,
الآن يقدر الناس أنه قد أدر نصف مليار دولار،
or will create about a half a billion dollars,
أو سيدر نصف مليار دولار،
in tax revenues for the city.
في عائدات الضرائب للمدينة.
We did a design competition,
أجرينا مسابقة تصميم،
selected a design team.
اخترنا فريق تصميم.
We worked with them to really create a design
واشتغلنا معهم لإنشاء تصميم
that was inspired by that wildscape.
مستلهم من تلك الزهور البرية.
There's three sections.
هناك 3 أقسام.
We opened the fist section in 2009.
افتتحنا القسم الأول في 2009.
It's been successful beyond our dreams.
وقد كان ناجحا بشكل يفوق أحلامنا.
Last year we had about two million people,
في السنة الماضية زاره مليونا شخص،
which is about 10 times what we ever estimated.
وهو تقريبا 10 في المئة مما كنا قدرناه.
This is one of my favorite features in section one.
هذه إحدى الميزات المفضلة لدي في القسم الأول.
It's this amphitheater right over 10th Ave.
إنه المدرج الموجود فوق الجادة العاشرة مباشرة.
And the first section ends at 20th St. right now.
والقسم الأول ينتهي في الشارع ال20. حاليا.
The other thing, it's generated, obviously, a lot of economic value;
الأمر الآخر، كما هو جلي، أدر الكثير من القيمة الإقتصادية؛
it's also inspired, I think, a lot of great architecture.
أظن أنه قد ألهم الكثير من المعماريين العظماء.
There's a point, you can stand here
هناك نقطة يمكنكم الوقوف هنا
and see buildings by Frank Gehry,
ورؤية بناء فرانك جيري،
Jean Nouvel, Shigeru Ban,
جان نوفيل وشيجيرو بان
Neil Denari.
ونيل ديناري.
And the Whitney is moving downtown
والويتني يتحرك إلى وسط المدينة
and is building their new museum right at the base of the High Line.
ويبني هناك متحفا جديدا في قاعدة الهايلاين تماما.
And this has been designed by Renzo Piano.
وهذا صمم من قبل رينزو بيانو.
And they're going to break ground in May.
سيضعون حجر الأساس في شهر مايو.
And we've already started construction on section two.
وقد بدأنا بناء القسم الثاني.
This is one of my favorite features,
هذه إحدا الميزات المفضلة لدي،
this flyover where you're eight feet
هذا الجسر حيث تكون على بعد ثمانية أقدام
off the surface of the High Line,
من سطح الهايلاين،
running through a canopy of trees.
تسير عبر مظلة أشجار.
The High Line used to be covered in billboards,
كان الهايلاين مغطى باللوحات الإشهارية،
and so we've taken a playful take
وهكذا اتخذنا مقاربة مرحة
where, instead of framing advertisements,
حيث، بدل تأطير الإشهارات،
it's going to frame people in views of the city.
ستقوم بتأطير الناس في مناظر للمدينة.
This was just installed last month.
تم تثبيت هذه الشهر الماضي فقط.
And then the last section was going to go around the rail yards,
ومن ثم القسم الأخير سيلتف حول ساحة السكك الحديدية،
which is the largest undeveloped site
والتي هي أكبر موقع متخلف
in Manhattan.
في منهاتن.
And the city has planned -- for better or for worse --
والمدينة قد خططت -- للأفضل أو للأسوء --
12 million square-feet of development
12 مليون قدم مربع من التنمية
that the High Line is going to ring around.
سيلتف حولها الهايلاين.
But what really, I think, makes the High Line special
لكن أظن أن الذي يجعل الهايلاين حقا فريدا
is the people.
هو الناس.
And honestly, even though I love the designs that we were building,
وبكل صراحة، ورغم أنني أحب التصاميم التي نبنيها،
I was always frightened that I wouldn't really love it,
كنت دائما خائفا من أنني لن أحبه،
because I fell in love with that wildscape --
لأنني وقعت في حب تلك الزهور البرية --
and how could you recreate that magic?
وكيف يمكن إعادة إنتاج ذلك السحر؟
But what I found
لكن ما وجدته
is it's in the people and how they use it
هو في الناس وكيف يستعملونه
that, to me, makes it so special.
ذاك، بالنسبة لي، يجعله في غاية التميز.
Just one quick example
مثال سريع واحد فقط
is I realized right after we opened
هو أنني أدركت مباشرة بعد أن افتتحنا
that there were all these people holding hands on the High Line.
أنه كان هناك كل هؤلاء الناس ممسكين بأيديهم في الهايلاين.
And I realized New Yorkers don't hold hands;
وأدركت أن النيويوركيين لا يمسكون بالأيدي؛
we just don't do that outside.
نحن لا نقوم بذلك خارجا.
But you see that happening on the High Line,
لكنك ترى ذلك يحصل في الهايلاين،
and I think that's the power
وأظن أن هذه هي القوة
that public space can have
التي يتوفر عليها الفضاء العمومي
to transform how people experience their city
لتحويل كيف يختبر الناس مدينتهم
and interact with each other.
ويتفاعلون مع بعضهم البعض.
Thanks.
شكرا.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)